Okay, so in this section,
we're just going to be
covering some basic quality
management methodologies.
You just need to be aware of these
methodologies.
You don't need to know them in any amount
of detail.
And for each of these methodologies, you
could be doing entire
certifications on them.
So for the PMP exam purposes, we're just
going to cover this at a very,
very, very high level.
You just need to be aware of just the
basic principles for each of these.
Okay, so the first one
I just want to briefly
talk about is this one
called 6 Sigma, right?
So, 6 Sigma is a methodology that's used
for process improvement.
I'm sure many of you have heard of 6
Sigma.
And again, you know, all of these,
their certifications by themselves.
Now, 6 Sigma, in the earlier video,
right, we covered the sigma levels, right?
So we covered 1 sigma, 2 sigma,
3 sigma, and then 6 Sigma.
So remember you need to know that one
standard deviation, one sigma is 68.26%.
Two standard deviations, two sigma is
95.46%.
Three sigma, 99.7%, 6 sigma
99.99.9.9.9.9.9.9.7%.
Now, a 6 Sigma organization
is one that is going to strive
towards having no more
than 3.4 defects per million.
That's really what 6 Sigma refers to 3.4
defects per million.
Whereas 1 sigma is 317,000.
500 defects per million.
Now, you don't necessarily
need to memorize
all of these defects per million, right?
You don't necessarily need to know all of
those except the six-sigma one.
Make sure you know that six-sigma is 3.4
defects per million.
Now another methodology, you just,
again, just need to be aware of,
is something called lean six-sigma.
And lean six-sigma
basically is a combination of
six-sigma and another
methodology called Lean.
It's kind of like a combination of the
two.
Now, Lean is used to streamline and
eliminate wasted activities, right,
and optimize the flow so you can deliver
value to the customer.
And Lean Sync Sigma also uses a similar
principle.
And Lean is, or Lean Six Sigma, seeks to
eliminate these seven
basic kinds of waste.
Now, you know, you may come across eight
types waste or nine types of waste,
but these are the main
seven and the seven that
you would need to know
about for the PMP exam.
So the seven kinds of waste then are
transportation, inventory, motion,
weighting, overproduction, over processing
and defects.
So one way of remembering those is this
little acronym here, right, Tim Wood,
right?
So transportation, inventory, motion,
waiting, over production, over processing,
and defects.
So all of these can be, you know,
wasted activities.
So the very simple example,
transportation, right.
That can be a major waste in activity.
If you have manufacturing plants in two
different locations, two separate
locations, both are
the, you know, each side
of the country, other end of the country.
And you've got activities that are
required in both, right?
One activity is performed in one
manufacturing plant, another activity
performed in another manufacturing plant,
well, obviously, then, there's a lot of
time wasted, moving products from one
manufacturing plant to
another manufacturing plant.
So we want to eliminate some of the wasted
time.
And same with all of these, inventory,
motion, waiting.
So again, we can
continuously improve some of
these processes by
eliminating these waste.
And that's really what Lean 6th.
Sigma, or Lean and Lean 6 Sigma,
you know, basically tries to address.
And both of these then uses the principles
of DMAIC and DEMADV.
And both DEMAC and DEMADVY are a
variation, a variant of the PDCA cycle,
rather plan do check act cycle.
Domek stands for defined, measure,
analyze, improve and control.
DEMADV stands for defined, measure,
analyze, design and verify.
Now, a couple of other terms, Kaizen and
Kanban.
Kaysen means continuous improvement.
That's basically what it means,
continuous improvement.
And it uses the PDCA cycle,
the plan do check hack cycle,
to make small but consistent
continuous improvement steps.
I mean, the whole idea is you cannot
improve your quality in one big step.
Or if there's any changes
you want to make,
organizational changes,
to improve quality, right?
It's going to be a lot more controlled if
you make small, continuous
improvement steps.
And then Canban, I'm sure a lot of you
have heard of Canban.
Canban actually also uses the principles
of Lean.
And Canban is more of a workflow method or
workflow management method.
And it's used for defining, managing,
improving services.
Right.
And basically, the whole idea is to
visualize the work, maximize efficiency,
continuous improvement as well.
Some of you may have come across Canban
board.
Well, not some of you.
You should all have come
across Canban boards, because
that's a term that you
need to know for the exam.
That's covered in a separate video as
well.
And the whole idea of Canban is to
visualize the work.
It's making sure that all resources
are utilized at the optimum level, right?
So canban, you do all resources are
utilised at the optimum level,
all resources are available just at the
time when you need them, right?
And so it's focusing on short-term flows
and visual, visual components, right?
So that's why we have a Kanban board,
which is a type of information radiator,
right?
So it uses a lot of white boards and
post-it notes and so and so forth.
It's something very, very visual.
And it uses this principle of just in
time.
And just in time, basically, we want to
try and eliminate inventory.
Now, another term that you may come across
is this one called the CMMI, capability,
maturity, model integration.
And this is more of an assessment made to
an organization as to what management
level there, or rather what project
management level they're at.
And again, it's a process
designed to improve
the overall quality of the organization.
And there are five basic assessment
levels.
So the organization could be at level one,
which is initial, right?
Initial, the initial
level where essentially
there is no project
management process in place.
Right?
Everything is reactive.
So there's no project management process
in place.
people are doing whatever they want to do.
And for all intents and purposes,
it's management chaos.
There is no standard procedure.
People are project managers.
They're just managing the project however
they want to on the fly.
We'll figure it out if it happens type of
thing.
Then you have level two, which is managed.
Level two is called managed,
where there is some project
management process in place,
but not everyone is following them.
Some people are following, some people are
not.
or some teams are following, some teams
are not.
So oftentimes, decision making is going to
be reactive.
With initial, it's always going to be
reactive decision making, right?
Because there is no project management
process in place, there's no planning.
In level two, right, if the organization
is at a level two, there is some
management process, but, you know, some
people are following some teams are not.
Then you have level three, which is
defined.
And defined means that there is a project
manager.
process and it's standardized across the
organization.
So think of it as having
some kind of project
management group in
place or a PMO in place.
So the PMO then is there to
create the standards and best
practices and then the teams
are following these best practices.
So decision making then is often going to
be proactive.
Then you've got quantitatively
managed where processes
are now measured and are
now measured and controlled.
So they are requiring adherence to those
standards.
And then the ultimate level five,
which is optimizing.
So that's the continuous improvement.
The continuous improvement in process in
place for all of the management standards.
So these are just some of the
quality management standards
that you need to be aware of
for the purpose of the PMP exam.
You don't need to know
any of these in any amount
of detail other than what
we just discussed here.
Thank you.